Louis Young

Full-stack Software Engineer (Web | Mobile)

Rue du Maupas 33, 1004, Lausanne, Vaud, Switzerland louis.young0420@gmail.com +41 22 548 01 93

A full-stack software engineer with 7 years of experience embracing a wide range of JavaScript technologies and creative UI/UX sense. I am a senior front-end engineer who has specialized in React and Vue.js, as well as other popular JavaScript frameworks and libraries such as Svelte, Solid.js, and Ember.js. I am a seasoned expert in mobile app development using lonic preferrably.

I have a passion for user-friendly interface and its performance, and am often being praised as a person who has good eye of design. Detail-oriented and meticulous attitude brings high-level quality assurance, meaning that I am obsessed with writing code that is clean, performant and reliable.

Backend experience of mine include mostly Node.js, Express, GraphQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL as well as more traditional technologies like Laravel and MySQL.

For more information: https://louisyoung.vercel.app

SKILLS

- ❖ JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, TailwindCSS, Material UI, ChakraUI
- React/React Native, Vue.js, Svelte, Angular, Solid.js, Ember.js, Ionic, Electron.js, Redux, Mobx
- Inertia.js, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Quasar, Gatsby, Livewire
- Node.js, Express, Nest.js, Laravel, GraphQL/Apollo, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Agile/scrum, Code review

EXPERIENCE



Zebedee, United States (Remote) - Front-end Software Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2021 - OCTOBER 2022

(Involved in Zebedee mobile app development and website development of Zebedee developer dashboard using React/React Native)

https://zebedee.io/app

https://zebedee.io/developers/dashboard

 Implemented complex UI elements with styled component and added core features such as bitcoin lightning invoice

- Reduced a fair amount of code lines and speeded up development cycle by replacing legacy Redux code with ReduxToolkit
- Migrated the whole React codebase from Flow to TypeScript to improve code reliability and legibility
- Owned product analytics feature using Mixpanel
- Wrote unit testing code using React testing library, Jest
- Blocket AB, Sweden (Remote) Front-end Web and Mobile Engineer

FEBRURY 2019 - JULY 2021

https://www.blocket.se

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=se.appcorn.Blocket

(One of the largest Swedish marketplaces with over 5 million items to find bargains & sell freely, Was responsible for building both web and mobile product of Blocket)

- Led mobile app development using Ionic, React, Capacitor
- Revamped UI with new figma design and refactored whole CSS code using styled-component for both web and mobile screens
- Solved device-dependent (iOS/Andriod) issues
- Optimized performance and improved UX by modularizing components, minimizing payload, code-splitting, lazy-loading, memoization/caching and image optimization
- Owned real-time update functionality using Socket.io
- API integration and state management using GraphQL Apollo



Pyszne Food Tech, Poland (On-site) - Full-stack Engineer

JUNE 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

https://www.pyszne.pl/

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yourdelivery.pyszne&hl=en&gl=US

(A platform for the biggest food delivery service in Poland, Mainly committed to full-stack development of the company's website.)

- Translated design team's UI/UX wireframes and mockups into well-organized and component-driven code while closely working with QA team and promptly reflecting needs of various clients and business objectives
- Involved in figma translation of Pyszne mobile app using Ionic, React
- Rewrote all class-based components to functional components with TypeScript and custom hooks
- Utilized benefits of multi-store management by introducing Mobx
- Increased search engine optimization and initial page loading speed using Next.js
- Worked on providing API endpoints with Node.js, Express, MongoDB and mongoose

Namtech Solutions, Singapore (Remote) - Full-stack Web Developer



MAY 2016 - APRIL 2017

(Gained reputation in the company by building customer-facing web applications exclusively using Vue.js)

- Implemented SSR (server-side rendering) and SSG (static side generation) on SPA using Nuxt.js
- Created unique spaces for marketing ads within landing pages
- CRM dashboard for admin systems and visual representation of data using jQuery, Chart.js
- Utilized Google Maps APIs paired with data visualization tools
- Built optimized queries and integrated APIs while working on backend using Laravel, MySQL

EDUCATION



Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (HKUST)

Bachelor of science (BS), Computer science

SEPTEMBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2015